

Bernardo Mondragón Brozon

Actuary & Full-stack Developer

Details

Mexico City, Mexico +52 1 55 3559 2033

DATE OF BIRTH

Links



https://github.com/BernardoMB



https://www.linkedin.com/in/bernardo

A https://independent.academia.edu/Be

Skills

Programming

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, R, Python, Java, C#, .Net, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, MySQL, SQL Server, Visual Basic, Objective C, Angular, RMarkdown, Python, Bookdown, MatLab, Maple, LaTeX, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, SQL, NodeJS,

Arquitect: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud, Heroku, Netlify,

Languages

English

Profile

Hard working man with +8 years of experience applying actuarial knowledge and developing all kinds of software solutions. Beign involved in several ambitious projects I have developed skills in insurance product development including software development and systems architecture. At the same time I consider myself a fully qualived actuary who has the confidence to work on my own initiative and the ability to play a key role in a leading company. I am a quick learner who can balance theory along with practical solutions. Right now I would like to join a company that is looking to hire the best talent, gain experience and face new challenges.

Visit bernardomondragon.net

Education

Bachelor's in Actuarial Science AUG 2013 - AUG 2018

Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de México (ITAM)

Applied mathematics and statistical methods to assess risk in insurance, finance and other industries and professions.

Experience

Senior Full-stack Developer NOV 2020 - PRESENT Zurich Insurance Company, Mexico City

.Net development of sureties administration system in Zurich North América. Financial Analysis, Underwriting Automation and Account Management. Technologies used: .Net, Blazor, Entity Framework, SQL Server, Git, Bitbucket, Jira, Ifrog, Redis, Dynatrace Jenkins, Linux VMs, Figma.

CoFounder JAN 2019 - PRESENT

Kalyptio.com

Design and execute strategic processes to deliver best quality software for our clients. I monitor that industry standards are met according to best coding practices. I have satisfied over 30+ customers providing them with software that suits their needs.

Senior Full-stack Developer JAN 2014 - DEC 2018 Neolinx de México SA. de CV., Mexico City

Successfully developed and implemented software solutions to manipulate and analyse data generated by the telecommunication industry for Mexico's Attorney-General's Office (PGR) and Mexico's Center of Investigation and Nation Security (CISEN).

Helped saving hundreds of lives and preventing thousands of crimes.

Succesfully parsed over 700 million CDR (call detail registries) from different random formats.

Full-stack Developer JAN 2013 - DEC 2013

Grupo Koomkin SA. de CV., Mexico City

Analyzed digital marketing campaigns data to maximize lead conversion rates for customers. Coded algorithms and designed UI UX flows for lead generation in digital platforms. Succesfully increased the lead convertion ratio for 40+ clients.

Producer JAN 2012 - AUG 2013

Ecorise Youth Innovations NPO, Austin TX

Pedagogue, designer, and producer of educational interactive and animated content. Animated over 40 educational video lectures for hundreads of students coursing elementary schoool.

Freelance

Instructor JAN 2019 - PRESENT

Mexico City

I teach online courses and create tutorials for students who want to get started in the software development industry.

I have taught hundreds of hours of programing lectures

Achievements

Insurance product on IUD failure risk MAY 2019

Mexico City

Developed a model to asses and manage IUD (Intra Uterus Device) failure risk for an innovative insurance product placement.

Succefully computed risk and market premiums, risk reserves, policy values, risk and utility margins and other actuarial measurements for the product under the Solvency II framework in order for it to be a viable and sustainable insurance product.

Advisor and judge appointment OCT 2018

Mexico City

I was appointed to be judge and advisor of the UNAMxHacks Hackathon organized by the National University of Mexico (UNAM).

Helped contenders to choose and implement different technologies in order for them to solve the event's challenges.